Yuliet Garcia

Phone: +1 305 731 6201

Email: <u>yuliet.garciapuente@gmail.com</u> **Portfolio:** <u>https://YulyGP.github.io/portfolio</u>

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

QA Manual tester skilled at test planning, writing test cases, test execution, bug logging, and test status reporting. Experienced in manual testing of web and mobile applications in an Agile software development work environment. Excellent technical communication, documentation, interpersonal, and reporting skills. Motivated hard worker with a professional attitude and work ethic. Ability to handle multiple tasks and work independently as well as in a team.

SKILLS

Agile and Waterfall Methodologies

Jira and Xray-for-Jira

Test cases creation

Bug report

Desktop apps testing

Mobile apps testing (Android and iOS)

Web apps testing

APIs testing (Postman)

SQL

Markdown

GitBook

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2022 - present

QA Lead

NexxtMission. Freelance. USA/Mexico

Coordinated and directed QA Testing efforts in an Agile Scrum-based/
Kanban-based methodology. Collaborated with product managers and developers to
define workflow procedures and manage Agile boards. Worked with the QA
automation team to plan and prioritize automation for various front ends, APIs and
services. Designed and executed test cases manually using black box and grey box
testing techniques for web-based and mobile applications in multiple environments.
Trained new testers, both in-house and off-shore, in the QA methodology and the
products used by our team and end-user companies. Documented testing
procedures, methodologies, or criteria. UI testing with Cypress and APIs testing with
Postman. Performed queries to relational databases with SQL language.

08/2019 - 02/2022

QA Manual Tester

Nexxtway. Freelance. Guadalajara, Mexico

Created test cases and performed regular, scheduled testing on all the apps, as well as on websites we developed as a company. Implementation of QA Methodologies for mobile and web applications. Attending and coordinating team meetings, Daily Scrum meetings, Sprint Planning, and Retrospective meetings. Proficient in QA testing using tools like JIRA and Monday.com. UI testing with Cypress and APIs testing with Postman. Write technical documentation and create tasks for developers.

03/2015 - 06/2019

Archivist and Quality Assurance Specialist CIFO-Veigas Archive. Havana, Cuba

09/2011 - 10/2014

Information Specialist Universidad de La Habana. Havana, Cuba

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011

Bachelor's Degree in Librarianship and Information Science, Universidad de La Habana. Havana, Cuba. Thesis: During my studies, I discovered a passion for technology which led me to be involved in a thesis that, along with other tasks and methodologies validation, requires me to design and perform multiple tests on a website. As a result, I detected several bugs and improvements and then worked with the development team to create a better version of that website.